why come back with me I want to talk to
you about the men of Nineveh remember
we've just seen that Nineveh was a
wicked city exceedingly wicked it was an
evil and adulterous generation it was so
wicked that Jonah himself thought yeah
there's no use to go preach the gospel
to this city have a question for you
if Jonah is a type of Jesus who are the
men of Nineveh if Jonah is a type of
Jesus who goes on this journey to reach
the hearts of that evil and adulterous
generation who is that evil and
adulterous generation who is who are the
men of Nineveh a type of us but I listen
to me do you have you ever looked at
yourself and thought to yourself
man there's no hope for me or like like
just kind of like Jonah treated Nineveh
do you ever feel like man I am so messed
up inside I really don't know if there's
any hope for me I don't know if I can be
reached look at all this evil within me
look at all this this wickedness within
me I don't know if God loves me enough
to redeem me beloved let me tell you
something if God loved the wicked and
evil generation back then he loves the
wicked and evil generation right now if
you look at yourself and say man no one
knows what I did last week no one knows
what I did the week before and if people
only knew they would not love me or God
would not love me let me tell you the
journey of Jesus Christ for three days
and three nights in the grave
demonstrates how much God loves the evil
and adulterous generation and yeah I
know that sounds crazy God doesn't love
the evil and Delta's generation no no no
God loves the evening delcious
generation he doesn't love the evil or
adultery but he loves the evil and
adulterous generation and that's why he
gives them the sign come notice with me
again
st. chapter Jonah chapter 3 verse 5 the
Bible says so the people of Nineveh
believed God thank you believed God and
proclaimed the fast and put on sackcloth
from the greatest of them even to the
least of them for the word came unto the
king of Nineveh and he arose from his
throne and he laid his roll from him and
covered him with sackcloth and sat in
ashes and caused it to be proclaimed and
published through Nineveh by the decree
of the king and his nobles saying let
neither man nor beast heard nor flock
taste anything let them not feed nor
drink water but let man and beasts be
covered with sackcloth sand crime moly
unto God yay let them turn everyone from
his evil way and from the violence that
had been in their hands who can tell if
God will turn and repent and turn away
from his fierce anger that we perish not
have a question for you
how wicked was this city how weak it was
this city so do you think that Jonah
going into the city and saying repent
would have all of a sudden changed this
wicked and adulterous City I mean I want
you to think about that what led the
king and the entire city to be like we
need to repent what do you think led
them to that what sign what
a man coming up out of the sea let me
ask you a question if you're sitting on
the beach one day just hanging out you
know yeah what a beautiful day
and you've been there for like hours
just enjoying the Sun and then you see a
man walking up out of the water first of
all if you did not die from fear then
the man said I'm from God I have a
message for you God is going to destroy
this city do you think the people of the
city might listen yeah listen carefully
beloved that sign of Jonah was given to
the Ninevites now we don't know how they
know because we're not we're not told it
could have been the people on the ship
there was a strong wind that was blowing
that ship and guess what that strong
wind could have blown that in the
opposite direction from which it was
going I'm sending you back to Nineveh we
have no idea it could have been the
people on the ship it could have been
someone on the shore but somehow or
another they knew that this man named
Jonah was not any old ordinary preacher
he had just had a very serious
life-and-death experience and when the
city saw it
the Bible tells us the entire city
repented listen to me beloved the Bible
says it is the goodness of God that
leads to repentance
I want you to check this out beloved God
was working out the salvation of a
wicked generation when they didn't even
know what was going on think about that
for a moment Jonah is out at sea the
wicked and evil and adulterous
generation have no idea that Jonah's
coming they have no eye
dear what's going on with Jonah but God
so loved the wicked and adulterous
generation that out at sea
he's like Jonah no no no we're gonna get
this right that to me is mind-blowing
when you're over there messing up God is
orchestrating your salvation he is
orchestrating events and working things
out
in a way that you are not even aware of
in order to try to save your evil and
wicked self God loves you and the
journey of Jonah is to demonstrate how
much God loves you that journey that
three-day journey was worth it God has
used for you don't ever think of
yourself as no good cut off beyond hope
beyond help that's what Jonah thought
yeah Nineveh no hope no use cut off
beyond help but that was not the case
beloved because as long as you have
breath God wants to use you as long as
you have breath God can turn you around
God can turn God can calm your storms
your storms God can bring you into
newness of life so I want you to check
this out because in Matthew 12 verse 41
the Bible says the men of Nineveh shall
rise in judgment with this generation
and shall condemn it because they
repented at the preaching of Jonas and
behold a greater than Jonah is here so
what is Jesus saying here the men of
Nineveh shall do what what shall the men
of Nineveh do they saw what they saw
what everyone they saw rise in what
alright what is that talking about can
someone tell me what Jesus means when he
said the men of Nineveh
rise rise in judgment what's he talking
about
he's talking about what resurrection so
Jesus saying listen guess who's going to
be resurrected who the men of Nineveh
wait that the same men of Nineveh that
represent that evil and wicked
adulterous generation yes you and I at
one time or maybe even now guess what
are or were the men of Nineveh and God
says listen the very ones who you
thought were written off the very ones
who you thought there's no hope for them
the very ones who you thought yeah God
really doesn't like them those very ones
the men of Nineveh because of the sign
of Jonah's of Jesus because they
repented at the death burial and or
because of the death burial and
resurrection of Jesus they will rise in
what in what not not check this out
remember when Jonah got mad when God
like didn't destroy the city and God
said what do you want me to destroy a
city of people who cannot discern
between the right hand and the left what
does that word discern mean wasn't mean
to discern you can discern something you
can one you can judge it check the saga
guess who rises in the judgment the very
people who at one time didn't even know
enough to judge correctly that's you
that's me
the very people who at one time could
not tell the difference between right
and wrong Jesus saying they are the very
ones that are going to rise in the
judgments why because they feared the
Lord and the Bible says the fear of the
Lord is the beginning of
wisdom they got wise what is wisdom how
do we get wisdom what did Paul say
wisdom was the preaching of Christ
crucified that is the wisdom of God and
so when they repented because of the
wisdom of God they in essence gained the
wisdom of God therefore beloved it is
the men of Nineveh who go forth with
this message fear God and give glory to
him for the hour of his judgment is come
and worship Him that made heaven the
earth in the sea and the font of water
the men of Nineveh preach this message
because they know what it's like to be
redeemed they have had an experience
with the death burial and resurrection
of Jesus Christ they know what it is to
repent because that message is what led
them to repentance